MAX MURPHY

Detroit, MI | 810-820-1908 | maxmurphymi@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Developer with experience in JavaScript, ReactJS, and Ruby on Rails. Professional experience in audio engineering/production that includes Avid Pro Tools, Adobe Audition, and Logic Pro X. Excited to contribute my success and aptitude in artistic sound engineering to create innovative solutions using new technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Ruby, HTML, CSS, SQL

Tools: React.js, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, DSA, OOP, Relational Databases, Git, Heroku, Firebase, p5.js

Audio: DAWs - Avid Pro Tools, Adobe Audition, Logic Pro X

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Hopper's Books - Flatiron School Final Project - Github | Live

Secure Rails/React app for an eCommerce site for a frog-themed bookstore.

- Developed front-end using React.js, and CSS to create a streamlined user experience.
- Built PostgreSQL relational database, Rails API structure, and dynamic seeding following the MVC framework.
- Dynamically rendered search page book data based on Google Books API endpoints.
- Utilized a many-to-many table association for individual user wishlist and purchase data.

Spats - Spotify Stats - Flatiron School Project Github | Demo | Live

React/Rails app for viewing your top tracks and artists on Spotify.

- Integrated a React UI with the Spotify for Developer's Web API to provide users with on-demand listening data.
- Compiled listening stats into seed data to create novel music recommendations based on user statistics.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Impact 89fm Production Director | Daytime Radio DJ

East Lansing, MI

09/2018 - 05/2020

- Utilized DAWs (Digital Audio Workstations) to produce weekly promos, PSAs, and other on-air content.
- Directed weekly volunteer meetings (of 12-15 participants) to facilitate understanding of audio production.
- Assisted in the production and broadcast of weekly live in-studio music performances.
- Established a welcoming atmosphere for music lovers as a daytime radio DJ.

Mac's Bar Sound Technician

Lansing, MI 08/2019 - 03/2020

- Managed and implemented audio recording and mixing equipment to run live sound for a 112 capacity venue.
- Set stage and sound in time-sensitive settings with efficiency to ensure timeliness of event.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Flatiron School

Remote

Certification - Software Engineering - Full Stack Web Development

07/2022

Michigan State University

East Lansing, MI

Bachelor of Art (BA) - Media and Information | Minor: Leadership of Organizations

05/2020

Internship - The Crofoot Presents - Production Intern - Assisted in production of high-budget, large scale music events

VOLUNTEERISM

Nonprofit Circle

Remote

Organization dedicated to building an online marketplace that facilitates growth and community where nonprofits can offer and claim surplus resources.

Frontend Developer - Volunteer

08/2022 - Present

- Member of engineer team that is creating a web app using NestJs, Postgres, ReactJs, Docker, and AWS.
- Work with UI design team to fulfill tickets based on component mockups.